MYKHAILO TRUSH

Phone: +353 83 8760561 Email: m.trush@ukr.net LinkedIn: ie.linkedin.com/in/michael-trush

Date of Birth: 2nd July 2000

Motivated ICT student at Technological University Dublin (BSc in Computing with IT Management and Data Analytics) with strong interpersonal skills seeking a Dublin based work placement position (February – June 2024) in information security/computer networking/devops.

SUMMARY

Developed a number of programs in college using Python and SQL. Also, gained valuable summer work experience in multi-cultural environment on the position of a Migrant Service Assistant under the International Organization for Migration Programme in Dublin. Motivated ICT student with strong interpersonal skills seeks internship opportunities and work placement position in information security, computer networking and devops.

IT SKILLS

- Can design and create database schemas.
- Capable of designing developing websites using, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap and HTML5.
- Can analyse data using tools like Excel and Python.
- Competent user of Windows and Linux Operating Systems in system administration.
- Design build and troubleshoot a network using routers and hubs using related tools.
- Configure a router using the Cisco IOS command set.
- Administer an Oracle 11G database server using Enterprise Manager and related SQL commands.
- Can write scripts in Powershell and Python.
- Have used cloud environments like Azure and AWS during my course.
- Have the knowledge how to apply ITIL service in business.
- Aware of cryptographic algorithms and protocols including both symmetric and asymmetric encryption algorithms, as well as hashing algorithms and digital signature protocols.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2020 – to-date Student - BSc in Computing with IT Management and Data AnalyticsTechnological University Dublin (Tallaght Campus). Currently in 3rd Year

2nd Year Modules studied, IT Scripting & Automation (B-); Client side Web Development (C); Discrete Mathematics 2 (C+); Adv Database Technologies (B+); Network Fundamentals (C+); Software Qual Ass & Testing (C); Project (B+); IT Services Management (D); Information Security (D); Database Admin & Analysis (D); Management Science (C); Routing & Switching Ess (B+);

1st Year Modules studied, Critical Skills Development (B-); Discrete Mathematics 1 (B); Business & Information Systems (B+); Visual Design & User Exp (B+); Computer Architecture (B+); Software Development 1 (C); Operating Systems Fundamentals (B); Database Fundamentals (B); Statistics (B); Social Media Communications (B); Systems Analysis (D); Software Development 2 (D);

May 2020 – Graduated St. Michael's College, Dublin, where I was a student from 2017-2020

Awarded the Leaving Certificate by the State Examinations Commission of Ireland

Significant Projects Undertaken

MQTT messaging system for a Bus Location

Description

A team project involving the development of a MQTT messaging system for a Bus Location topic, that allows users to easily send messages to one or many recipients. Features included Publish/subscribe messaging, clients subscribe to topics and receive messages published to those topics. Creation of DB, webpage as well as UI for the users to see incoming messages.

Challenges faced:

Creation of the user friendly interface (JavaScript)

Technologies & Tools Used:

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL, MQTT broker (Mosquitto), Git, Docker, Azure DevOps

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2022 - September 2022 Migrant Service Assistant in Dublin, Ireland, International Organization for

Migration (IOM), UN Migration Agency (special short-term ungraded

contract).

Organisation Description: The International Organization for Migration (IOM) is part of the United

Nations System as the leading inter-governmental organization promoting

humane and orderly migration for the benefit of all.

Main Responsibilities

Provided migrant service to applicants, provided migrants with accurate information, organized the files of the applicants in the required order in full compliance with the IOM Service Standards, maintained high level of accuracy of data capture, informed management of any problems or issues immediately while regularly suggesting how to improve efficiency and service, performed other duties.

March 2019 – April 2019 Member of the Precinct Election Commission for the Election of the President

of Ukraine, abroad polling station №900027, Embassy of Ukraine, Dublin,

Ireland.

Organisation Description: The temporary body established to organize and conduct the election of the

President of Ukraine among Ukrainian citizens living in Ireland.

Main Responsibilities

Participated in organizing and providing the Election of the President of Ukraine in a free, fair, and transparent manner, in accordance with the Law of Ukraine "On Election of the President of Ukraine". Registered voters and issued ballots. Conducted the voting process and counted the votes. Compiled and submitted the election results to the Central Election Commission of Ukraine.

INTERESTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Sporting

• Certified scuba diver. Snowboarding and solo gym enthusiast.

Cultural events

 Participated in the presentation of Ukraine at the International Diplomatic Charity Bazaar in 2019 and 2022 in cooperation with the Embassy of Ukraine to Ireland.

Volunteering

Assisted in providing consular services in the Embassy of Ukraine to Ireland, May - September 2023.

REFERENCES

Available on request